SAUL (Sulayman) SALLAH

Boyds, MD | Phone: 240-708-5477 | Email: Saulsallah1@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saulsallah/

GitHub: https://github.com/Saulstice | Portfolio: https://saulstice.github.io/SolPortfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a B.S. in Information Science and a specialization in Cyber-Security & Privacy. Accomplished at using knowledge of user behavior to help create user-friendly, clean, useful applications. Known by colleagues to be a driven, fast learner and great communicator.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript - HTML - CSS - MongoDB - Node - Express - Ajax - React - MySQL - Python - Java - UI/UX Testing - Quality Control

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

• **GW FULL-STACK CODING BOOTCAMP** (APRIL 2020 – OCT 2020)

- Gained the essential skills for front-end web development, covering HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, as well as command line fundamentals and API consumption.
- Learned the skills necessary to engineer a full stack web application by working with servers, databases, and other back end technologies, and connecting them to the front end.
- Gained the skills needed to optimize web applications for speed and efficiency as well as develop progressive web applications that combine the best of mobile and web apps.

• EQUAL LEVEL: INTERN (MAY 2018 – AUG 2019)

- Helped develop and maintain "search connectors" that integrated online ecommerce environments using HTML and Python.
- Performed UI/UX testing and Quality Control on software tools and user interfaces by testing against sets of requirements.
- Constructed documentation for customer enablement.

• UMD DIVISION OF IT: TECHNICIAN (AUG 2018 – NOV 2019)

- Troubleshot software to diagnose and resolve problems for professors.
- Installed and configured appropriate software and hardware according to specifications.
- Provided orientation "walkthroughs" to professors on how to operate software and equipment.

PROJECTS

ShowTrack App | GitHub: https://github.com/Saulstice/two | Deployment: https://tranquil-waters-31767.herokuapp.com/

- ShowTrack is a social network application that allows users to add, collect, and rate shows or movies they have finished, are currently watching, and/or plan to watch in the future. Show Tracker also allows users to interact with each other through the discussion feature and global feed.
- Made with Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Heroku, MySQL, Sequelize, Unogs API via RapidAPI, and Handlebars.

Re:fresh Web App | GitHub: https://github.com/Saulstice/Refresh | Deployment: https://saulstice.github.io/Refresh/)

- This web application allows users to search for outdoor activities that they can do near their chosen location.
- Made with JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and various APIs.

Employee Database | GitHub: https://github.com/Saulstice/employeeDB

- A solution for managing a company's employees, roles, and departments in a SQL database.
- Used the MySQL NPM package to connect to my MySQL database and perform queries, and the Inquirer package to interact with the user via the command-line.

README Generator | GitHub: https://github.com/Saulstice/ReadMeGen

- A command-line application that dynamically generates a professional README from a user's input using JavaScript, node, and the Inquirer package.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: The George Washington University – Full Stack Web Development Certification (*Completion: Fall 2020*) **University of Maryland, College Park** – Information Science Major (*Graduation: Fall 2020*)

Relevant Completed UMD Courses

- 'Dynamic Web Applications', 'Object-Oriented Programming' (Java), Python, 'Database Design & Modeling' (SQL), Statistics, 'User-Centered Design', 'User Needs', 'Foundations of Entrepreneurship', 'Entrepreneurial Decision-Making in Technology Ventures', 'Organizations, Management and Teamwork', 'Technologies, Infrastructure and Architecture'.